a good old trusty weight bench may be
one of the most often overlooked pieces
of gym equipment but if it weren't for a
weight bench you wouldn't be able to rep
out your bench presses plus you can do
dumbbell rows tricep dips and even focus
on core work rett fitness sent us over
their fb 5000 competition weight bench
and so today i'm going to break down my
findings in a complete review for you
all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
review i've got the rep fitness fb 5000
in this video i'm going to take you
through everything this weight bench has
to offer from the price some pros and
cons and of course who should
or maybe who should not buy this weight
bench but before we get started with any
of that
i gotta let you know we have reviewed a
lot of weight benches on barbin.com and
if you want to browse our best list just
google barbind best weight benches and
you can find out for yourself which ones
that we like the best
okay so let's talk about what i like
about the fb 5000 since it is a
competition bench it's designed to meet
international powerlifting federation's
height standards so if you're a
competitor out there you can properly
prep for your next competition with this
weight bench it's made from 11 gauge
steel and it's rated at a thousand
pounds meaning it's built for the long
haul and it's gonna be able to handle
that heavy weight that you might be
lifting but it only weighs 62 pounds so
it's super easy to pick it up move it
around plus you have a set of wheels and
a handle that's gonna make it even more
portable the four inch thick pad is made
from a non-slip vinyl so it's gonna help
you stay in place while you're lifting
plus it's pretty comfortable and
honestly who doesn't like that
okay so with all those nice things being
said there's a few issues that you might
run into when looking to add the fb5000
to your home gym
let's talk about the money first
it was designed to be a cost effective
option when it comes to a competition
weight bench but you're still spending
over 200
if that's out of your budget you can
always look for a cheaper weight bench
out there but it's not guaranteed that
that bench is going to meet the
competition standards like this one does
rep actually has two cheaper options
available on their website but one is
made with 14 gauge steel and they're
both rated at 700 pounds instead of a
thousand like this one is if you're
somebody who wants an adjustable weight
bench you might not want this one either
because
as you can see it's flat and it doesn't
adjust and third if you're somebody
who's really not loading up a bunch of
heavy weight for your bench presses you
may not need this weight bench and you
might want to consider another one that
has a lower weight capacity
okay so let's talk about the money
you're gonna be looking at spending on
the fb5000 it actually comes in three
different pricing options five different
colored options and your choice of a
narrow or wide pad
it comes in red blue metallic black
matte black and the clear coat that you
see here which i think looks awesome
so with the narrow pad those colored
options are going to be around 210
dollars
and it'll be around 280 with that clear
coat option so if you wanted the wide
pad those colored options they're going
to be about 240 and over 300
if you want that clear coat like we have
here if you're tight on space you can
also purchase a wall mounted hanger so
that you can store your weight bench
while you're not using it but it's gonna
cost you about forty dollars or so
while you may be spending over three
hundred dollars on this weight bench and
i know that's a lot of money there's
actually other competition weight
benches out there for nearly four
hundred dollars but if you have plenty
of space you don't need that wall
mounted hanger you don't really care for
the clear coat option or that wide pad
you're gonna be spending around 210 in
total which is a really good deal
especially once you consider the quality
of this bench now this is definitely an
investment purchase but if you compete
in powerlifting competitions this is a
really good option to consider it's
gonna handle that heavy weight you're
lifting and that 11 gauge steel could
keep this in your home gym for nearly 20
years
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the fb 5000 so like i said it only
weighs 62 pounds but don't let that fool
you it is as sturdy really as you could
ask for it to be that 11 gauge steel is
professional quality which you'll most
often find in a professional gym and it
could keep this weight bench in your
home for nearly 20 years
i have the wide pad bolted in to the
frame but like i said you do have the
option of a narrow one so this one's two
inches wider than that narrow pad and
that may not seem like a big difference
especially for that extra money you're
spending but if you're a broad person
you might be interested in this one
because it might make you more stable
maybe even more comfortable too
the footprint of this weight bench is
just under eight square feet which is
another thing that you got to consider
when you're looking to add this to your
home gym
[Music]
okay so let's go a little bit further
into detail now on the features of the
fb5000 let's start with the padding here
like i said it is made from a non-slip
vinyl so it's going to help you stay in
place while you're lifting you get a
little bit sweaty like i said i also
think it's pretty comfortable
it does feature a tripod foot design so
if you're somebody who's really
particular about how your feet are
positioned while you're lifting you
don't have to worry about that here
because you have plenty of space at your
feet you do have a set of wheels and a
handle it's going to make moving this
thing around your home gym
really easy and as i mentioned it is
available in red blue metallic black
matte black and this clear coat option
[Music]
all right guys i'm going to walk you
around the 5000 now talk about all the
features that it does have
starting with the framework this is made
from 11 gauge steel but it does have
that tripod foot design which is really
cool because it's going to give you
optimal foot placement while you're
lifting sticking with this area right
here you do have the handle
with the set of wheels it's going to
allow you to move it around your home
gym with ease and i really really love
this clear cut option here just got to
mention that one more time
since this weight bench is designed to
meet
international powerlifting federation
height standards i'm going to measure
this for you guys so you can see it does
in fact meet those
standards as you can see it's just under
17 inches right there making it ideal
for those power lifting competitions
and since you do have the option of a
wide pad or a narrow pad i actually have
both of them for you so i'm going to
show you guys
that wide pad is in fact two inches
wider than the narrow one
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the rep
fitness fb 5000 well if you're a
powerlifting competitor you're going to
really like the fact that this does meet
competition standards so it's going to
help you prep for that next competition
if you want a flat bench that's going to
last you for decades
this 11 gauge steel is a really nice
touch plus it's rated up to a thousand
pounds so it's gonna handle all that
heavy weight you're lifting and if
you're somebody who's really particular
about your foot placement while bench
pressing this tripod foot design is
definitely for you because it's gonna
give you optimal room while you're
lifting
[Music]
okay so what about the people who maybe
shouldn't buy this weight bench okay so
while this was designed
to be a cost effective competition
weight bench
you're still spending potentially over
if you were to get that wide pad with
the clear coat and the wall mounted
hanger
so if that falls out of your price range
you can definitely find cheaper options
out there
rep actually has two options that are
cheaper like i said
but those may not meet competition
standards and they may not last as long
as this weight bench can if you're not
competing in power lifting competitions
then you really just may not have much
of a need for this weight bench and the
amount of weight that it can handle
and then third if you don't have around
eight square feet of space
in your home gym then you may just be
out of this one completely so
be sure to measure everything out and
that you do have enough space before you
even begin to think about lifting with
this weight bench
[Music]
well that's a wrap for today's review
over the fb 5000 this is a great weight
bench to consider especially if you're
competing in power lifting competitions
and you want to train from home the 11
gauge steel is professional quality and
it makes this weight bench super sturdy
it could be the last one you ever need
to purchase
thanks for sticking around everyone hope
i answered a few questions you might
have over the fb 5000 and you know the
drill stay on the lookout for my next
review
and in the meantime head over to
barbin.com and you can read over more
about this weight bench and all the
other products that we have reviewed
just search barban rep fitness fb 5000
review and you can read over everything
that we discussed here today i'll see
y'all next time
[Music]
you